{"tossups": [{"question": "In 2013, a central figure in this case went on a speaking tour with Mike Hiestand. In<em> Morse v.</em> <em>Frederick</em>, the precedent set by this case was not followed in favor of one set by<em> Bethel v. Fraser</em>.<em> Hazelwood</em> <em>v. Kuhlmeier</em> restricted some of the freedoms granted by this case, whose dissent was written by Hugo Black and John Harlan. This case was precipitated when students refused to remove black armbands protesting American involvement in Vietnam. For ten points, name this Supreme Court case that forced an Iowa school to recognize the First Amendment rights of schoolchildren.", "answer": "<b> Tinker</b> v. Des Moines (Independent Community School District)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Julia Domna was the daughter of a priest associated with this deity. Coins under the emperor Probus depict this deity riding in a four-horsed<em> quadriga</em>. A temple in the<em> Campus Agrippae</em> was dedicated to this deity by the emperor Aurelian, who established the official cult of this deity. Though not related to Christianity, this deity\u2019s feast day was celebrated on December 25th. Elagabalus was assimilated with, for ten points, what Roman deity with a name that translates to \u201cUnconquered Sun?\u201d", "answer": "<b> Sol Invictus</b> (accept<b> Elagabalus</b> until \u201cDecember\u201d is read; accept<b> Unconquerable Sun </b>before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This location can be seen from Dante\u2019s View, and was the site of the prehistoric Lake Manly. The Timbisha tribe lives at Furnace Creek in this landform, which was made a national monument by Herbert Hoover in 1933 and a national park in 1994. Francis Marion Smith employed twenty-mule teams to transport borax out of this area on the border of the Mojave and Great Basin Deserts. Badwater Basin reaches 282 feet below sea level in, for ten points, what California valley, the lowest point in North America?", "answer": "<b> Death Valley</b> (accept descriptions of<b> Death Valley</b> National Park; prompt on Mojave Desert before mentioned)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s 1979 summit with Jimmy Carter ended with Carter unsuccessfully proselytizing to this man. This man briefly became a communist after his older brother died during the Autumn Uprising of 1946. After seizing power in the May 16 coup, this man\u2019s administration passed the Yushin constitution and instituted the New Village Movement to modernize the rural economy. This man survived an attempt on his life in the 1968 Blue House Raid, and was later assassinated by Kim Jae-gyu, his intelligence chief, in 1979. For ten points, name this third President of South Korea, a dictator whose daughter is a recently impeached president.", "answer": "<b> Park Chung-hee</b> (prompt on either name alone)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This series inspired the title of a 2005 Eugene Jarecki documentary analyzing the military-industrial complex. The fifth entry in this series opens with footage from<em> Alexander Nevsky</em> and<em> Peter the First</em>. A statement by Henry Stimson was edited into the first entry of this series, which contained footage from <em>Triumph of the Will</em>; that work was released four years before its creator directed<em> It\u2019s a Wonderful Life</em>. For ten points, name this series of seven pro-American propaganda films created by Frank Capra during World War II.", "answer": "<b> Why We Fight</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {"question": "English cities that produced this resource were often given the suffix \u201c-wich.\u201d L\u00a8uneburg\u2019s Hanseatic status was due to this good, which was shipped from L\u00a8beck to the Scania Market. M\u00a8unich was founded using revenue from this resource. The<em> gabelle</em> was a controversial French tax on this good. Venice and Ferrara feuded over the production of this good in the Commachio, leading to a namesake war. For ten points, name this good, which comes in rock and sea varieties and is used to preserve fish.", "answer": "<b> salt</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A fire at this man\u2019s home destroyed his book<em> Dialogues against the Peripatetics and Galenists</em>, in which he rejected the non-experimental methods of ancient thinkers. While dissecting a black man, this man discovered the mucus that was responsible for skin pigmentation. This scientist, who is thought to have been the first to directly observe red blood cells, was appointed papal physician by Pope Innocent XII in 1691. For ten points, name this Italian biologist who names a set of renal corpuscles in the kidney and a set of excretory tubules in insects.", "answer": "Marcello<b> Malpighi</b> (accept<b> Malpighian</b> corpuscles and/or tubules)", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {"question": "This battle is described in the most common lyrics of the song \u201cLillibulero.\u201d A year after this battle, an evacuation of troops called the Flight of the Wild Geese occurred following the Treaty of Limerick. This battle is celebrated on \u201cthe Twelfth,\u201d and it featured a successful river crossing by the Blue Guard. The loser of this battle had thrown his signet ring into the Thames two years prior. This battle occurred during the War of the Grand Alliance and is named for a river. For ten points, name this 1690 battle, fought after the Glorious Revolution, at which William III decisively beat James II in Ireland.", "answer": "Battle of the River<b> Boyne</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The Angel Phase of these people is speculated to have led to the emergence of the Caborn-Welborn group. These people established the Parkin site along the St. Francis River, a location considered to be part of the Southeastern Ceremonial Complex culture. In order to mark the passing of solstices, these people built a timber circle that archaeologists dubbed Woodhenge. These people constructed the pyramidal Monks Mound at an urban center near modern St. Louis. For ten points, name this Pre-Columbian Native American civilization that inhabited the Cahokia site by a namesake river.", "answer": "<b> Mississipian</b>s (accept<b> Mississippian</b> people, culture, etc.; prompt on Native Americans before mentioned; anti-prompt on Cahokia before mentioned) <b>Second Quarter</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This location was rediscovered by Adam Render and Karl Mauch, the latter of whom sent press reports to Germany noting he had discovered Solomon\u2019s temple. The Eastern Enclosure of this location\u2019s Hill Complex is speculated to have held eight carved soapstone birds. The Great Enclosure is part of, for ten points, what 15th century city ruins near the town of Masvingo that lends its name to an African country with capital at Harare?", "answer": "<b> Great Zimbabwe</b> (prompt on Zimbabwe)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A ship originally named after this battle was captured during the Raid on Medway. Though injured during this battle, the winning side of this battle led a cavalry charge from the Sulby Hedges. After being shot, Philip Skippon decided not to retreat in order to maintain troop morale. Marmaduke Langdale commanded a group of Covenanters during this battle. For ten points, name this 1645 victory for the New Model Army during the English Civil War, a year after the Royalists lost at Marston Moor?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Naseby</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This phrase is inverted and ironically quoted in the negative in Part IV of \u201cHugh Selwyn Mauberley.\u201dThis phrase is followed by the line \u201cDeath pursues the man who flees\u201d in its original use. A poem with this title was meant as a response to Jessie Pope\u2019s jingoistic poetry; that poem admonishes the reader to not tell this phrase \u201cwith such high zest/To children ardent for some desperate glory\u201d before denouncing this phrase as the \u201cOld Lie.\u201d For ten points, name this phrase, originally by Horace, that was used as the title of an anti-war poem by Wilfred Owen.", "answer": "<b> dulce et decorum est</b> pro patria mori (prompt on \u201cIt is sweet and proper to die (for one\u2019s country)\u201d)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {"question": "Tensions between this man and one president he served were chronicled in his autobiography titled <em>As I Saw It</em>. After France\u2019s withdrawal from NATO, this man reportedly asked de Gaulle \u201cDoes your order include the bodies of American soldiers in France\u2019s cemeteries?\u201d This man earned the ire of Israel after claiming that the attack on the<em> USS Liberty</em> was intentional. After the assassination of John F. Kennedy, this advocate of containment was asked to stay on by Lyndon Johnson. For ten points, name this Secretary of State during the 1960s.", "answer": "David Dean<b> Rusk</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man used the quote \u201cart is eternal, life is short\u201d while anonymously submitting his opera<em> Vakula</em> <em>the Smith</em> to a competition. In support of wounded Serbian veterans of a 1876 conflict with the Ottoman Empire, this man penned his \u201cMarche slave\u201d for charity. Part of \u201cLa Marseillaise\u201d [mar-sigh-ehz] is followed by cannon fire in one of this man\u2019s works, which was composed to commemorate the Battle of Borodino. For ten points, name this Russian composer of the<em> 1812 Overture</em>.", "answer": "Pyotr<b> Tchaikovsky</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A new cathedral on the same site was consecrated in 2000.", "answer": "Cathedral of<b> Christ the Saviour</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This event inspired the Broadway play</b><em><b> War of Wealth</b></em><b>, which was released three years later. The National Cordage Company became insolvent during this event, which also saw</b> <b>the collapse of the Philadelphia and Reading (+)</b> <b>Railroad. A march in Masillon, Ohio</b> <b>was organized in response to this event by Coxey\u2019s Army. The Bland-Allison Act had been followed up with the (*)</b> Sherman Silver Purchase Act three years before this event, contributing to a lack of redeemable gold during this event. McKinley\u2019s election as president was assisted by, for ten points, what financial panic during Grover Cleveland\u2019s second term?", "answer": "<b> Panic of 1893</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 2013, this country\u2019s leader was forced to land in Vienna after there were erroneous suspicions that his plane was carrying (*) </b> Edward Snowden. This country has been led by the Movement for Socialism since 2005, part of Latin America\u2019s Pink Tide. For ten points, name this South American country currently led by President Evo Morales.", "answer": "Plurinational State of<b> Bolivia</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>The Second Moscow Death Batallion of these people were the last army unit to defend the Provisional Government during the October Revolution. The February Revolution</b> <b>started with mass protests on a holiday (+)</b> <b>celebrating these people. One of these people</b> <b>assassinated Gavril Luzhenovsky and later led the radical Socialist Revolutionaries. A Russian Communist Party department devoted to these people, (*)</b> Zhenotdel, controversially forced de-veilings in Central Asia, streamlined divorces, and legalized abortion. For ten points, name this group of people that included the revolutionaries Alexandra Kollontoi and Maria Spiridonova.", "answer": "Russian and/or Soviet<b> women</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This city grew according to a plan created by Patrick Geddes, and its Engel House is the first building here to make use of pilotis. A central roundabout here is named for the wife of its first mayor, Meir Dizengoff, and the world\u2019s largest collection of (+) International Style buildings can be found in its \u201cWhite City.\u201d This city took its name from the title of a novel by Theodor (*)</b> Herzl and was founded in 1909 on the northern outskirts of Jaffa. Bauhaus architects fleeing Nazi Germany developed the architecture of, for ten points, what coastal city, the second-most populous in Israel?", "answer": "<b> Tel Aviv</b>-Yafo", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>25 liters of wine. The term \u201cmagdeburgization\u201d arose from an incident in which this man\u2019s</b> <b>troops pillaged Magdeburg. This man, who was killed crossing the (+)</b> <b>Lech River during</b> <b>the Battle of the Rain against the Swedes, gained notice for leading the Catholic League to victory at White Mountain. The Imperial army was led by (*) </b> Albrecht von Wallenstein and this man, who was born Johann Tserclaes. For ten points, name this Bavarian commander of the Thirty Years War whose service granted him the title \u201ccount.\u201d", "answer": "Count (of)<b> Tilly</b> (accept Johann<b> Tserclaes</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>One holder of this position controversially remarked that black people made a game of having children out of wedlock called \u201cjewels in the crown.\u201d Another holder of this position eliminated his state\u2019s poet laureate position to remove the author of \u201cSomebody Blew</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Up America,\u201d Amiri Baraka, and resigned this position after appointing his lover as</b> <b>Homeland Security Adviser. Christine Todd Whitman and Jim McGreevey have held this position, whose power was recently used to gain political revenge by (*)</b> closing two lanes on the George Washington Bridge during rush hour. For ten points, name this political position currently held by Chris Christie.", "answer": "<b> Governor of New Jersey</b> (prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>After the Revolution, this man was given an estate near Edisto called \u201cBoone\u2019s Barony.\u201dThis man\u2019s wife Catherine provided Eli Whitney with the funds to create the cotton gin. At Valley Forge, George Washington appointed this man (+) Quartermaster General. This man, whose troops faced down Lord Rawdon\u2019s command, suffered a loss that prompted Charles James Fox to say \u201cAnother such victory would ruin the British Army!\u201d; that loss to (*)</b> Charles Cornwallis came at the Battle of Guilford Court House. For ten points, name this \u201cFighting Quaker,\u201d a Revolutionary War general and leader of the Southern Campaign.", "answer": "Nathanael<b> Greene</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker!", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>The first holder of this position previously chaired a conference regarding rights to seal hunting between the U.S. and Britain and served in the Japanese Famine Relief Committee; that man was Charles Sumner (+) Hamlin. According to</b><em><b> The Age </b><b>of Turbulence</b></em><b>, another holder of this post was highly influenced by Ayn Rand. A 21st century holder of this post explained that \u201cThe (*)</b> Great Moderation\u201d has reduced volatility in business cycles due to a decrease in bank oversight. For ten points, name this post, once held by Alan Greenspan and Ben Bernanke and currently held by Janet Yellen, that oversees the U.S. banking system.", "answer": "<b> Chair</b>person of the<b> Fed</b>eral Reserve (System) (accept<b> Chair</b>man and/or<b> Chair</b>woman of the<b> Fed</b>; prompt on \u201cChair\u201d alone)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}